Shiva Sharma

Cary, North Carolina | (919) 793-4494 | shivash0520@gmail.com

OBJECTIVES:

Full Stack Javascript Web Developer with a background in graphic design, business management, marketing, sales and customer service. Experience in working with quality driven teams on team-based projects with recognition for complex problem solving abilities and hard-working nature.

LINKS:

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/shiva-sharma05/ | GitHub: https://github.com/ssh1sharma

Portfolio: https://personal-react-site.netlify.app

TECHNICAL SKILLS:

HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Materialize, JavaScript, jQuery, ExpressJS, NodeJS, ReactJS, MongoDB, MySQL, Mongoose, APIs, AJAX, JSON, ES6, Sequelize, C#, ASP.NET, Azure DevOps Tools, Heroku, Netlify, cPanel, GIT, Drupal CMS, UI/UX Design, Dreamweaver, Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, Desktop Publishing Apps

PROJECTS:

<u>Job-and-News-Search App</u> | Third Party API (Search job listing or news articles in any category)

Role: Created HTML page using CSS framework and used jQuery ajax method for the server-side APIs call. Javascript was used for the DOM manipulation and browser-based local storage API.

<u>COVID-19-Tracker App</u> | MERN Fullstack (Allows the user to create a profile, use a symptom checker and map to find out information and related news.)

Role: Utilized ReactJS library, HTML, Bootstrap CSS at the front-end and NodeJs Javascript runtime, Express framework and MongoDB database to the back-end. Used Informedica, NY Times and Azure server side APIs for symptom checker, data, and news. Also, the Passport and Bcrypt middlewares were used for user authentication and data encryption.

<u>Weather-Dashboard App</u> | Third Party API (View and save weather conditions for a specific city)

Role: Utilized HTML, Bootstrap framework to create the app UI and used jQuery ajax method for the server-side OpenWeatherMap API call. Used Javascript for DOM manipulation.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

AssetWorks LLC, Junior UI/UX Developer

10/2020 - Current

- Creating prototypes for new product functionalities and designing/optimizing new and existing user interfaces by utilizing frontend web development technologies such as HTML, CSS, Javascript, C#, ASP.NET and DevOps tools.
- Testing product's user interface features and actively attending product teams and daily scrum call meetings to achieve business goals and objectives.

Freelance Web Developer, Web UI/UX Designer, Graphic Designer

- 01/2020 Current
- Currently working for NCNC, Morrisville, NC. Working as a graphic and web designer in a team to
 publish web contents, magazine, business ADs, collateral designs. Utilizing Adobe CC design tools,
 HTML, CSS, Javascript to create and maintain the contents. Working to migrate the website to the
 Wordpress CMS.
- Currently working as a web designer at the Cary Gallery of Artists, Cary, NC. Managing gallery's business-website and online shopping site.

Rasha 7 LLC, Cary, NC | Manager

05/2015 - 12/2019

- Effectively led a team of 10+ to meet and exceed goals and objectives of a dine-in restaurant.
- Built a strong customer base to run the business effectively. Utilized email and advertising marketing strategies to build customer flow.

Whole Foods Market, Cary, NC | Graphic Designer/Store Artist/TM

08/2006 - 05/2015

- Worked in the marketing department to design and create marketing materials and signs.
- Collaborated with store leadership, department managers and team members to determine effect and progress of marketing work, inventory levels, and production problems.

Walmart, Germantown, MD | **Department Manager**

02/2004 - 08/2006

- Effectively collaborated with Store Leadership and Project Managers to complete daily business.
- Successfully managed 10+ employees in the Health and Beauty department with scheduling, training and helping.

EDUCATION:

Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp University of North Carolina	1	Chapel Hill, NC	2020
AAS Degree in Advertising and Graphic Design Wake Tech College		Raleigh, NC	2011
Web Technology Certified Wake Tech Community College		Raleigh, NC	2011
Digital Photography and Fine Arts Montgomery College		Germantown, MD	2004
Bachelor of Business Management Tribhuwan University		Kathmandu, Nepal	1998